# Arjun Ankathatti Chandrashekara

1133 Ashland Rd • Columbia, Missouri 65201 • (573) 639-3762 arjun.ankathatti@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/arjunankathatti

#### **SUMMARY**

Full stack software developer with 4 years of industrial experience in design, development, and implementation of enterprise web applications using JAVA/J2EE framework and object-oriented programming. Excellent technical, analytical, problem-solving skills with a strong passion for technology and ability to work independently or within a team environment.

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Missouri** 

Columbia, Missouri

Master of Science in Computer Science, GPA 3.8/4.0

Graduation: December 2018

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Research Assistant, Networking and Multimedia Lab, University of Missouri

August 2016 - Present

#### **Multi-Cloud Resource Recommender**

- Design and development of web application using Struts2 and Tiles framework
- Coded JDBC calls in the DAO classes to access the Oracle database tables
- Worked with 3rd party API's such as Amazon AWS Java SDK
- Published paper "Recommending Resources to Cloud Applications based on Custom Templates Composition" in the ACM Computing Frontiers Conference, 2017

**AWS EMR Cluster** 

May 2017 - August 2017

- Automated the deployment of EMR cluster to support data science class which saved operational costs by 75%
- Created Bootstrap actions to install Jupyter Notebook server and PySpark kernel on EMR cluster using Boto3
- Automated the generation of EC2 Security Groups with firewall exception and SSH Key Pair
- Used CloudWatch to monitor metrics, set up billing alerts and alarms that further reduced the costs by 20%

# Database Programmer Analyst, MU Division of IT, Columbia, Missouri

**January 2017 – June 2017** 

- Designed and developed .NET based solution using C#, ASP.Net, ASP.NET MVC
- Built utility class libraries and created product critical stored procedure in SQL Server
- Developed responsive web UI using Bootstrap, CSS which increased website usability by 30%

## System Engineer, Infosys, Bangalore, India

October 2014 – July 2016

- Implemented business logic in service layer classes and created model classes
- Developed UI in Spring MVC framework using JSP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery
- Proposed Pentaho Spoon ETL tool for data migration and transformation, which saved 60% of the effort and time
- Held in-person and web-based workshops to share the knowledge of Pentaho Spoon tool with the wider team

# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

#### **Neuroscience Gateway (CyNeuro.org)**

January 2018 – Present

- Designed and developed the gateway portal using Laravel PHP, AngularJS, Bootstrap4
- Developed embeddable chatbot widget on the portal using JavaScript and JQuery
- Created RESTful API endpoints using Python and FLASK micro framework
- Managing Linux/Unix application servers and basic system administration

## **Budget – Expense Manger**

**July 2018 – September 2018** 

- Developed reusable user interface components and implemented them with Redux
- Compiled JSX with babel presets, bundled the modules with webpack, and tested the apps with Jest
- · Setup authentication, user accounts, routing, form validation and configured the DB storage

## **Online Tic-tac-toe Game**

May 2018 - August 2018

- Real-time two-way communication between client and server using Socket.IO and Node.js
- DOM manipulation to update game state using JQuery based on the events triggered by the Server
- Implemented a game room concept which enables users to join the game based on unique game ID

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages

: Java, Python, PHP

Web & scripting

: HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, CSS, AJAX, JSON

Frameworks & Libraries

: Struts2, Flask, React.js, Socket.IO, Boto3, node.js

Database

: SQL Server, Oracle 11g, MySQL

• Software Tools and others

: Git, SVN, Gulp, Sublime, Eclipse

AWS

: EC2, EMR, ELB, Lambda, RDS, IAM, S3, CloudWatch